bottlenotes.com 2015-06-29

# Bottlenotes

### **Bottlenotes, Inc. Privacy Policy**

**Effective Date: November 10th, 2008**

### TABLE OF CONTENTS

Introduction  
Active Collection of Personal Information  
Passive Collection of Information  
Cookies  
Web Beacons  
Embedded Scripts  
Mobile Device Identifiers  
Information from Third Parties  
Use of Personal Information  
Disclosure of Information  
Third Parties   
Service Providers   
Promotions   
Co-Sponsors   
Business Transfers   
Legal and Safety Obligations   
Submissions   
Parental/Age Advisory   
Security   
Advertisements   
Third Party Web Sites   
Agreement to International Information Transfers   
Modifications to the Privacy Policy  
Questions/Contact Us

### Introduction

Bottlenotes, Inc. ("Bottlenotes," "we" or "us") owns and operates [www.bottlenotes.com](http://www.bottlenotes.com/ "www.bottlenotes.com") , [www.winecyclopedia.com](http://www.winecyclopedia.com/ "www.winecyclopedia.com"), and other web sites that are co-sponsored by Bottlenotes and other third parties ("Co-Sponsored Sites") (collectively, the "Sites").  
This Privacy Policy applies to information collected by us through the Sites and does not apply to information obtained or collected by us in any other manner unless expressly stated in this Privacy Policy. Please take a minute to read this Privacy Policy so that you understand our information collection practices, such as the types of information we collect from visitors to the Sites ("Visitors") and how we may use that information. Please also review our Terms of Use, which governs your use of the Sites.  

### Active Collection of Personal Information

To access or take advantage of certain features of the Sites, we may request that you provide personal information. "Personal Information" is information about you that is associated with your name or identity, such as, name, mailing address, e-mail address, credit or debit card account number, birth date, telephone number, or purchase information. Personal Information may also include "Demographic Information," such as your gender, marital status, salary, purchasing habits, or similar information.  
Personal Information may be requested and collected at various locations and on various forms on the Sites, including but not limited to: registration forms for newsletters and other e-mail communications; registration for membership to the Sites; registration for participation in contests, sweepstakes, auctions, surveys or other promotions that may be offered on the Sites (collectively, "Promotions"); when you submit an inquiry via the Sites; when you submit an order for wine or other products; or when you communicate or otherwise interact with us via the Sites. You may always elect not to submit Personal Information, however, as a result, you may not be able to access certain of the Sites' features and functionality.  
We may also provide you opportunities to submit Personal Information about other individuals. For instance, you may choose to send a notice through the Sites to a friend regarding content offered by the Sites. We will not use the Personal Information of these individuals for any other purpose unless we disclose otherwise at the time you provide the information.  
If you have registered as a member of any of the Sites, you may update or modify some of the information that you actively provided through the Sites, including your e-mail marketing preferences, by logging into your member account. In addition, you may deactivate your member account.  

### Passive Collection of Information

In addition to the Personal Information that you actively provide to us, we or our third party service providers may use a variety of technologies to automatically collect information about you when you use the Sites. This information may include Demographic Information, browser type, operating system, clickstream data, IP address, mobile device identifiers and other information.  
The methods that we and our service providers may use to automatically collect such information include the following:  
  **Cookies** : Cookies are data files that are placed on a computer when it is used to visit a web site. These cookies may be used for many purposes, including, without limitation, tracking user preferences and web pages visited while using the Sites. You may disable cookies using your browser's preferences. However, some features of the Sites may not function properly or may operate slowly if you disable the cookies.  
  **Web Beacons** : We may include small graphic images called web beacons, also known as "Internet tags" or "clear gifs," in our web pages and e-mail messages. Web beacons may be invisible to you, but any electronic image inserted into a web page or e-mail can act as a web beacon. We may use web beacons or similar technologies for a number of purposes, including, without limitation, to count the number of visitors to the Sites, to monitor how users navigate the Sites, to count how many e-mails that we sent were actually opened or to count how many particular articles or links were actually viewed.  
  **Embedded Scripts:** An embedded script is programming code that is designed to collect information about your interactions with the Sites. It is temporarily downloaded onto your computer from our web server or a third party we work with, is active only while you are connected to the Sites, and is deleted or deactivated thereafter.  
  **Mobile Device Identifiers:** Certain mobile service providers uniquely identify mobile devices and we or our third-party service providers may receive such device information if you access the Sites through mobile devices. Certain features of the Sites may require collection of mobile phone numbers and we may associate that phone number with the mobile device identifiers. Additionally, some mobile phone service providers operate systems that pinpoint the physical location of devices that use their service. Depending on the provider, we and our third-party service providers may receive this information.  
If we associate any such passively-collected information with Personal Information about you, we will treat the combined information as Personal Information. 

### Information from Third Parties

We also may, from time to time, obtain supplemental information about you from third party sources. If we combine the information we receive from these third party sources with Personal Information about you, we will treat the combined information as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy.

### Use of Personal Information

We may store and use Personal Information for many purposes including to:  
• Send you e-mail or mobile communications, such as newsletters and promotional offers, on behalf of Bottlenotes or third parties;  
• Send you information regarding the Sites, including features, products or services;  
• Contact you with regard to surveys or Promotions in which you have participated;  
• Complete a transaction or authorize a purchase that you have requested;  
• Verify the accuracy of information you submitted to us;  
• Collect and respond to reports of inappropriate conduct by Visitors;  
• Conduct aggregate research or analyze the performance of our products or services;  
• Monitor, administer or improve the Sites or develop future web sites;  
• Audit the use of the Sites;  
• Customize the advertising and other content on the Sites;  
• Contact you about the Sites or inquiries you make through the Sites;  
• Monitor compliance with the Terms of Use  
and other applicable agreements and policies; or  
• For internal business purposes or the purposes disclosed at the time you provide your information. 

We will not use the information you provide via a “contact us” or other similar form or address to contact you for marketing purposes unrelated to your request unless you agree otherwise.  

### Disclosure of Information

We may, in our sole discretion, share with third parties information that is not associated with your name or identity, such as web site usage information, anonymous Demographic Information, and aggregate user statistics. We may share Personal Information with third parties as described at the time you provide the information and under the following circumstances:  
  **Third Parties:** We may share Personal Information about you with third parties for marketing or other purposes if you consent to such sharing at the time we collect the Personal Information. If you agree to such disclosure, then the use of the Personal Information we share will be subject to that party's privacy policy. Therefore, you will need to contact that third party directly if you decide that you do not want that party to use your Personal Information. 

  **Service Providers:** We may share your Personal Information with third party service providers so that they may perform certain services for us, such as web site hosting, order fulfillment, clearing and processing credit and debit card payments, or performing other services on our behalf. 

  **Promotions:** If you choose to register for Promotions offered on the Sites, your Personal Information may be disclosed to third parties in connection with such Promotions, including, without limitation, in connection with winner selection, prize fulfillment and as required by law, such as on a winners list. Also, by entering a Promotion, you are agreeing to the official rules that govern that Promotion, which may contain specific requirements of you, including, except where prohibited by law, allowing the sponsor(s) of the Promotion to use your name, voice and/or likeness in advertising or marketing associated with the Promotion.  
  **Co-Sponsors:** We may share Personal Information that you provide to us through a Co-Sponsored Site with the Co-Sponsor of that Site. The Personal Information that is shared with a Co-Sponsor will be subject to that Co-Sponsor's privacy policy. In those cases, a link to the Co-Sponsor's privacy policy will be provided on the Co-Sponsored Site. You will need to contact that Co-Sponsor directly if you decide that you do not want that Co-Sponsor to use your Personal Information.  
  **Business Transfers:** We reserve the right to disclose and transfer Personal Information about you including, without limitation, during the course of any due diligence process: (i) to a subsequent owner, co-owner or operator of a Site; or (ii) in connection with a corporate merger, consolidation, restructuring, sale of substantially all of Bottlenote's stock and/or assets or other corporate change.  
Legal and Safety Obligations: We may disclose your Personal   **Information:** (i) if we are required to respond to subpoenas, court orders, legal process or other valid law enforcement measures; (ii) at the request of governmental authorities conducting an investigation; (iii) when we believe in good faith that the law requires disclosure; (iv) to verify or enforce compliance with the Bottlenotes Terms of Use  or other policies governing the Sites; (v) whenever we believe disclosure is necessary to limit our legal liability or to protect or enforce the rights, interests, or safety of the Sites, visitors to the Sites or other third parties; or (vi) to respond to an emergency.  
  **Submissions:** Pursuant to our Terms of Use, we may publish your name, voice, likeness and other Personal Information in connection with any submissions you may make to the Sites.  

### Parental/Age Advisory

The Sites are not directed to children or individuals younger than 21. We do not knowingly collect or solicit Personal Information from anyone younger than 21. In the event that we discover that we collected Personal Information about a child or individual younger than 21, we will delete the Personal Information.  

### Security

No data transmission over the Internet or electronic storage of information can be guaranteed to be 100% secure or hacker proof. While we have implemented security measures, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or through the Sites.  

### Advertisements

Advertisements from third party advertisers ("Advertisers") may appear on the Sites. Advertisers may compile information about the advertisements that appear to you while you are using the Sites and which advertisements you click on. The Advertisers may use cookies, web beacons and other methods of passively collecting such information. The collection of such information through these methods may allow the Advertisers to track each time you are sent an online advertisement from that Advertiser. These Advertisers may use this information to deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy does not cover the methods for collecting information used by these Advertisers or the use of the information that the Advertisers collect.  

### Third Party Web Sites

There may be hyperlinks on the Sites to other web sites or locations that are operated and controlled by third parties ("Third Party Web Sites"). These Third Party Web Sites may use their own cookies, web beacons and other technology to independently collect information about you. In addition, these Third Party Web Sites may solicit Personal Information from you. We make no representations regarding the policies or business practices of such Third Party Web Sites and have no control over the type or use of the information that is collected by these Third Party Web Sites.  

### Agreement to International Information Transfers

The Sites are operated in the United States. If you are located in the European Union, Canada or elsewhere outside of the United States, please be aware that any information you provide to us will be transferred to the United States. By using any of the Sites or providing information to Bottlenotes, you fully understand and consent to the transfer, collection, storage and processing of the information in the United States. In addition, you fully understand and consent to the transfer, collection, storage and processing of the information outside of the United States by Bottlenotes to service providers located outside of the United States.  

### Modifications to the Privacy Policy

We reserve the right, at any time and from time to time, for any reason in our sole discretion and without prior notice or liability, to change, modify, amend and/or update this Privacy Policy. Therefore, you should review this Privacy Policy before submitting any information to Bottlenotes through any of the Sites. We will collect, store, use and share your Personal Information in a manner consistent with the Privacy Policy in effect at the time you submitted the information, unless we receive your consent to the new or revised policy.  

### Questions/Contact Us

If you have questions about the Sites or this Privacy Policy, including how we may collect, store, use or share information about you, please contact Customer Service at [customerservice@bottlenotes.com](mailto:customerservice@bottlenotes.com) .
